Less than a month to go before the NFL
draft. Today we're breaking down the
defensive backs, a chat with Field
Yates, and the latest Patriots news.
Let's do it. With the 31st pick, the New
England Patriots.
>> Welcome everybody to Patriots Draft
Countdown presented by Bud Light. Easy
to drink, easy to enjoy. Bud Light, the
official beer sponsor of the New England
Patriots. And guys, we are just under a
month away from the draft. We've been
plowing through these shows. Hey, we're
going to talk a little about the
defensive backs, but first talk a little
latest news, minor bit, Paulie Josh Doss
released him.
>> Yeah, I mean, I saw this coming a little
bit uh a couple of weeks ago when they
decided to reup Tommy Devito, gave him a
two-year deal. Um, sort of, you know,
let him wet his beak a little bit. That
told me that they were comfortable with
him as the backup. Now, I didn't tell
you exactly that Dobs is is definitely
out, but it it did tell me that they
thought enough of Tommy Devito that he
could be the main backup. I would expect
something down the road though guys in
terms of a developmental guy uh whether
it's sometime in day three of the draft
or sometime soon but you need probably
need another arm to come in. Of course,
we already did our quarterbacks episode,
but
>> we named a few of them in that. So, any
anybody you want to bring back into the
>> Well, I I I just I think it's a
interesting conversation of are you
going for like a raw ceiling kind of guy
that's got some tools, that's got some
athleticism, uh you know, like a guy
like Hannes King comes to mind that that
can maybe uh not not even just play
quarterback, but maybe do the whole
Taesm Hill thing and play a little bit
of offensive weapon, let's call it,
receiver. or are you really looking for
who's going to be Drake May's backup for
the next 10 years, you know, and you're
trying to go that route. But either way,
whether it's having a third arm in
training camp, an emergency quarterback
come game day, it makes a lot of sense
to carry three quarterbacks on the
roster even into the season. So to only
have two quarterbacks under contract
right now, there's definitely at least
one more quarterback coming. maybe even
two as a UDFA signing as well to get to
four to go into training camp because
you don't want to you don't want to get
into a preseason game where you have to
play your top two quarterbacks, you
know, a lot. So, you're you're going to
have another at least one more guy. But
I am interested to see which way they go
in the draft in terms of are they just
looking for that steady backup, you
know, not to say anything bad about
this, but a Brian Hoyer perhaps or
someone like that or are they looking
for somebody that has a little bit more
ceiling that has some raw athleticism to
him?
>> Maybe you develop them, maybe turns into
an asset. I mean, I always think it's
good business to draft quarterbacks
generally. It seems like they have a
need for them. One more thing I want to
talk about the guys Jackson Smith and
Jesus signed, you know, huge deal,
highest paid wide receiver now in the
game. We saw in the Super Bowl how good
well maybe not specifically in the Super
Bowl as much as he did during the
regular season,
>> but T uh just again the wide receiver
market. We're reminded yet again that
these guys are very valuable and that
NFL teams once you find one, you better
hang on to them.
>> Yeah, I mean I the dream is for the
Patriots to get a guy of THAT LEVEL ON
THE offensive side of the ball to pay
that. Right now we got on the defensive
side of the ball. The price of the brick
keeps going up. So hopefully Gonzo's
next, but the dream is to get a receiver
like JSN here. Don't know when that'll
happen, but that's the goal.
>> Well, we got a lot here on tap today.
First up, though, Tiss and Chris are
going to break down maybe some prospects
worth trading up for the Patriots in the
first round. I to I spoke with Field
Yates and then we got a nice long
breakdown of all the safeties and
quarterbacks that could possibly fit the
Patriots. Check it out.
>> Chris, we usually talk about mocks here.
>> Yeah, we do.
>> But that being said, I we're going to
skip on the mock drafts this this
segment and we're going to go to mock
trades.
>> All right. like I I like trade here and
there. So I I wrote a little sheet here.
I'm just going through a couple
scenarios that might happen. So as we
all know, the Patriots have the 31st
pick, right?
>> So there's a lot you can do with that,
right?
>> So scenario one, which I think is
unlikely, but it's a scenario. It's
there. Trading up,
>> right? We're at 31. Yeah.
>> What do you think it would take? Like
like my thing is if you love a guy
example Kenyan Sadique Oregon tight end
if he's there at 25 27 I don't think
he's going to drop that far. Let's just
say he's there.
>> Yeah,
>> that guy's a dog.
>> He is.
>> So like what what do you do? What do you
do if you're Elliot Wolf?
>> If I'm Elliot Wolf, I don't know if I'm
trading up in this draft. Okay.
>> I really don't.
>> I think I think you either stay put, try
to get an edge rusher. I I think your
main focus early on is edge. again, if
you can trade up and maybe get like a
stud wide receiver or like I don't know,
something out of the ordinary that we
wouldn't fully expect,
>> which is way up there in this
>> way up there. Yes. Way up there. I think
that's the that's the difference in that
in that category. But I mean, for
Sadique, he's a great great tight end. I
think you can still hold out enough uh
later in the draft for a solid tight end
in that category. I I personally like
the trade down thought though.
>> We'll get to the trade down. I know, but
I'm getting ants.
>> I know. I know. I know. So, one more
thing with the trade up is like what do
you think it would cost? Because let
let's say you're going the to 27,
>> right? I mean, you're giving up your
second
>> you're giving up your second. Obviously,
you're giving up your first, you're
giving up your second and I mean, maybe
a fourth
>> fourth or a few dicey for next year,
too. But next year, a lot of talent. I
don't think we're going to see a lot of
those ones moved for next year. Hence
the hold up on some of the trades this
year,
>> right? I I just I just don't think
logistically it makes a lot of sense for
the Patriots to move up right now,
especially with where they're kind of
sitting and who they're looking for. I
think there will still be guys available
kind of either where they are or if they
were to go back into early second round
type of spot.
>> We'll get there, Chris. Don't worry, I
got you. All right. So, that's I think
we can agree that's the most unlikely.
Yes.
>> All right. So, we got scenario two.
>> Trading for a proven vet.
>> All right. Okay. So, we we saw the
murmurss with AJ Brown. It kind of seems
like the first round picks the hold up,
which it should be. Yes. AJ Brown's up
there. But listen, I uh you're a Pats
fan like me. We've been hurt a lot by
these by these prospects. You know, not
everyone turns out to be Drake May or
Christian Gonzalez. True.
>> That that being said, if there's a vet
out there, you have a need. Well, I'm
just throwing a name out there. Buddha
Baker, safety, Cardinals. I think he's
29, 30. Yeah. I don't know if I'd give
the first up for him, but you know,
>> it's it's an option. It's No, it is for
sure. I mean, a guy like Buddha Baker,
you kind of have that in Kevin Ber right
now. So that's why I mean way different
play style. Way different play style,
but you kind of had that. No, I know you
do. I know.
>> But you are talking about a guy like AJ
Brown. Yep.
>> Do you have fully what it's worth for
him at least with this year's picks? I
think you're going to be looking at next
year's picks more importantly,
especially with the upcoming draft and
the importance of ne next year's draft.
Um, but I think if we're just talking
about the the sake of AJ Brown's trade
scenario,
>> I think the Patriots are going to give
up a first. Most likely you're going to
give up a third, maybe.
>> So, you're locked in on the first. Yeah,
>> I I don't know if the first is in play.
>> I do. I I actually do think that first
that first round pick is in play uh for
the Patriots, you know, trying to get AJ
Brown. Um, but, you know, I I just think
bigger picture here. I think you need to
protect your picks because you don't
want to be I don't I don't want to say
careless, but you know, you want to be
cautious.
>> 100%. This is the this is the the
nucleus of your franchise, right?
>> Okay. All right. So, I was team trade
the pick for a vet, but as stuff has
fallen into place, I I don't know if
that's the move anymore. When I say a
vet, I mean like I'm I'm shooting for
the stars here, you know? Oh, you know,
I'm thinking Jedi, but that's not Evan
would tell me to shut up. So, we're
going to scenario number three, which is
the one you want, which is trading back,
which the Patriots have done before. I
mean, they they they did it in 2022 with
Co. They trade back, got Cole Strange.
So, it we're not afraid to do that as a
franchise, right? So, that being said,
what can you get? Like, I I ran a couple
mocks of in the mock draft simulator of
what a trade would look like with the
31st. So, the first one I had was
Carolina for the 31st pick offered their
second, their third, and a 2027 fifth.
Mhm.
>> Uh the Chargers offered their second,
their third, a 2027 fourth and sixth,
and the Giants offered their second, and
a 2027 fourth. So, kind of seems like
you're getting two picks plus some next
year,
>> right?
>> You just got to weigh how high up your
second is because you're obviously your
own seconds further back in the second
round.
>> It is. It is. And I mean, I think that's
the thing though, like you use that
first round pick and you're flexing out
to try to get more either earlier in the
second, well, at least one earlier in
the second and one earlier in the third,
my opinion, because
>> again,
>> you don't want to lose its value
necessarily, but I do think there's
enough guys, especially at the edge rush
edge rusher position, that if you were
to trade back and pick, say you're
picking sixth in the second round,
>> y
>> I think there's still value. you could
still get the guy that you're kind of
looking for
>> 100%. Let's say hypothetically Casey
Conception at 31. Okay, just stays there
and some team picking high up in the
second like let's hop up. They don't
take him. There's a chance he could keep
slipping and then you boom, you got two
seconds. The only thing the only thing
the thing is with the first you get the
fifth round option which is obviously
valuable. I'm team if you like the guy
and this is your guy take him.
Especially in the first you get the
fifth option.
If if you're confident, go with your
guy. But if in your in your world,
right, you talk about Casey Conpion
being there at 31, right? You trade back
and he still keeps falling and then you
get Messador and Conpsion. You got an
edge, you got a wide receiver in LA.
>> See you. I'll see you later. I'll see
you next time.
>> So So if we rank these scenarios, which
one? What's first?
>> I think you know what my favorite
scenario is. Straighting back. I I
>> If they sit, sit.
>> Yep. If you're not gonna sit, don't move
up.
>> Okay.
>> I think trade back.
>> Unless there's a dog there.
>> Get right. But collect more picks, more
value picks because right now the
Patriots have one pick in the first
round. Obviously,
>> one pick in the second round, one pick
in the third round. They have a couple
of fourths and they got a bunch of six
round picks.
>> So, I think something needs to happen
with the six round picks. Sort of a long
day for start working your way up a
little bit with those eight six round
picks. Yeah. No, not literally. But um
you know you got to make some sort of
adjustment there. I think you have
enough leverage especially in the fourth
round picks and six round picks kind of
work something up keep trading up in the
draft. I don't know if it's necessarily
going to involve that first round pick
trade scenario or second round pick
trade scenario. You don't know. But if
they're going to move from that first
round, I think they move back, collect
more second round picks, potentially a
second and a third. Kind of add more to
the sweeten the pot a little bit even
though you're going a little bit further
back in the draft.
>> 100%. All right, guys. Thanks for tuning
in this segment. We'll see you on the
next one.
>> All right, we're excited now to be
joined by Field Gates from ESPN to break
down the Patriots offseason here. A
little bit of free agency, a little bit
of look forward to draft. field, thanks
for taking the time here to hop on with
me.
>> No problem, Bruce. Glad to be with you
today.
>> So, let's just start off with free
agency. You know, the Patriots um seemed
like a lot of one forone moves, you
know, digs out, dos in, etc. Uh just
what were your impressions here of the
Patriots moves through the early part of
free agency.
>> Yeah, well said. And you could take it a
step further with moves like Draymond
Jones in, Caleb, Chaon out. They play a
different style of game, but still guys
that you expect to be or in the case of
Chaon was a a starter, a very solid
starter for them at that. He was
especially great down the stretch and in
the playoffs. Draymond Jones, you expect
to be a starting edge rusher for this
franchise as well based off the
familiarity, the skill set, and also the
money, which is always a good thing to
follow during free agency. So, it feels
like an off season that um I feel like
there's more to be done. And that what I
mean by that is it feels like the
Patriots still have some cards left to
play. And it's not just the draft. It's
other ways, other levers to pull to
continue to improve this roster.
Obviously, it's in very good shape. They
made the Super Bowl this past season,
but there are a couple of items on the
to-do list that I think this team is
going to still look to address.
>> Well, one of those items, could it be AJ
Brown? I mean, there's just so much
talk. I mean, Patriots fans have been
talking about AJ Brown forever.
>> We've been doing this dance for a couple
years now. it feels now they're saying
maybe after June 1st. What are your
thoughts on that whole potential coming
to fruition finally? AJ Brown to the
Patriots. Is it real?
>> Yeah, I think where I've landed with AJ
Brown is that until either he comes out
himself and publicly commits to wanting
to be a Philadelphia Eagle for 2026 and
beyond, or until we get to the start of
the regular season, I'm going to believe
there's a real possibility that he has
traded. There's just been so much
speculation and so much smoke and from
some of the top insiders in the game. My
colleague Adam Shester has been talking
about the possibility of an AJ Brown
trade and certainly made it seem like
that is still in play. And he's
referenced that the Patriots are one of
the teams that still are a logical
landing spot perhaps at least in my
estimation the most logical landing spot
for AJ after June 1st. And I think
probably most viewers and listeners to
this program already know this, but
after June 1st, it becomes a lot more
palatable from a salary cap standpoint
for Philadelphia to trade away AJ Brown.
So that's a long time to have to wait.
Still two and a half more months from
when you and I are talking right now.
But for a player of this caliber and for
a deal that would most likely involve
draft capital, you can wait until June
2nd to have a guy that would immediately
give the Patriots their best offensive
weapon for Drake May to distribute the
football to.
>> Just one more question for you, Phil,
about the offense. I just I felt like
this was a real Josh McDaniels kind of
offense. You know, we see Reggie Gilliam
come over from the Bills. Josh got to
have his fullback. You know, you take a
little bit of a chance on on Vera Tucker
who's had some injuries but has a high
upside. Uh it seems to me, you know, you
got to get a blocking tight end there
from Miami as well. Seems like they
really are focused on maybe building the
toughness, the physicality, short
yardage was an issue for them last year.
Uh and then you also bring in Dobs. How
do you see that all coming together?
>> Yeah, totally agree. Especially on those
first three players that you referenced,
kind of the identity of what they bring
to the table. Reggie Gilliam,
hard-nosed, excellent fullback, also
great on special teams. He'll help in
that regard. Julian Hill, a name that I
don't know how many people knew a whole
lot about Julian Hill. He's got a very
interesting background prior to playing
in the NFL, but to your point, he is
going to help the running game as well.
Played in that very unique scheme in
Miami where he was on the move a lot and
carving out some paths for guys like
Devon Achan who of course was excellent
for Miami these past couple of seasons.
Um, but short yardage has to be better.
Uh, you know, there's always this push
pull when you've got a quarterback like
Drake May who can run the tush push and
assuming of that stays in 2026 and
beyond, but also a quarterback that you
want to protect. And then beyond that,
you've got a player in Trayvon Henderson
who we know how electric Trayvon is. He
was unbelievable for stretches last
season, but his role decreased down the
stretch and into the playoffs. He feels
like the kind of guy that's at his best
running between the tackles with
somebody leading the way for him. He's
just not going to be this gigantic power
back and Raandre was great last season,
especially down the stretch. It was kind
of the reverse of how Trayvon's impact
played out. But I think that both of
those guys will benefit from having a
hammered head in front of them. Jack
Westover gave them good snaps last
season. Jack much more of an angular
blocker, the kind of guy that's a factor
in the passing. Well, at least he was
during college, a factor in the passing
game, but not the kind of fullback that
we have seen for a lot of years for the
Patriots with Josh McDaniels. Most
recent versions include the likes of
YaKob Johnson and maybe Reggie Gilliam
can give you a bit more of what Yak gave
you for those years in New England.
>> Oh, I love the Yak shout out, of course.
Love, love our German Yakob Johnson.
But, uh, let's get let's get into the
draft a little bit at field. And this
is, you know, weird. We're last couple
years, you're talking top five picks and
it's going to be one of two or three
guys. Now we're back to picking at the
bottom of the first round where, you
know, I always like that spot a little
bit because maybe something gets pushed
down that you weren't really expecting.
Maybe it's not a huge need, but there's
a very talented player. A lot of talk
about this edge class. It's still a huge
need for the Patriots. Every time I look
at a mock draft, I get down to that 31st
spot. Who's the edge? You know, it's
it's either somebody has to slip through
the cracks or maybe you're reaching a
little bit. Just what are your general
thoughts down there at 31st overall here
in this draft? Well, there's two ways in
which this is trickier to forecast for
the Patriots than the past couple of
years where it was pick three and then
pick four. And that third pick two years
ago was especially easy when it was
going to be a quarterback and there were
three outstanding prospect at the top
and you just take whoever is left over.
And I think the Patriots are thrilled
that Drake May is the guy they got. I
think frankly all three teams are
thrilled with how it played out, but
that's a different conversation for a
different appearance here on the show.
Um, this year it's more difficult, not
just because of the fact that there are
infinite scenarios that could take place
between 1 and 30, the 30 picks that
precede the Patriots, but also it's this
very unique draft class. It's a draft
class that's I would say breath the blue
chip talent. There are a few guys, but
not a lot of real difference makers. And
what you find, and earlier today, I
dropped my top 50 on ESPN.com, and I try
to be judicious and in checking comments
uh on social media when you do things
like that. However, I'd imagine there
are probably some people that are
frustrated about certain players being
too low, maybe a couple of players being
uh eyebrow raising in terms of how high
they are, but this is that draft class.
This is very much a choose your own
adventure draft class. I don't think
there's tons in the way of consensus. So
for the Patriots at 31, I think the
needs to me would stack up in some order
of continue to add add rushers. A wide
receiver with the caveat that if an AJ
Brown trade might get done after June
1st, it's not quite as pressing of a
need. I think a number two tight end or
number three tight end, I however you
want to categorize it, a guy that can
give you a little bit more than what we
have seen so far from Julian Hill as a
pass catcher. Uh with Hunter Henry going
into the final year of his current
contract. Uh those are some of the
positions that come to mind for me. Uh
and then continuing of course to hammer
along the offensive line. I think they
have their five guys if they were to
play a game tomorrow. Um but I al you
know they have a chance to have their
five guys if they play a game tomorrow.
I certainly think you know the ABT
signing gives them some real versatility
and upside when he is healthy. Uh but
they need to continue to add depth there
as we saw during the playoff and you
face off against the best pass rushers,
pass rushers and pass rushes as a group.
Uh you got to have not just five guys
you can really count on but a great
protection plan and also some depth.
>> Love what you're saying about the edge
and the tight end groups. I mean those
are two position groups at the combine.
We heard Vable Elliot Wolf both mention
those. I mean the tight ends totally
hear what you're saying. Like I just
they get younger, get a young one of
these athletic guys. Max Clair from Ohio
State, one that I like. But want to talk
about two other positions down there,
though. And you had Caleb Lomu from Utah
as a tackle, uh, taken in the 31st
overall in your first mock draft, which,
you know, to me, I think that's a need,
too. I'd also look at the safety
position. You know, does one of those
guys get pushed down a little bit. They
just signed Kevin Byer. He's on a
one-year deal. He's still playing at a
high level. You've got Craig Woodson
kind of locked in, but that could be a
long position of need. are tackle and
safety maybe two darkh horse positions
down there at 31st overall that you
could see them consider.
>> I try to remind consumers of my content
this all the time is that like other
than quarterback everything's kind of a
need for the Patriots because the NFL is
a unpredictable and there's a salary
cap. So players that are currently
fixtures may not be fixtures for the
next five or six years. So, I think that
offensive line just in general has
talked about a need. Safety could be a
need as well. And I think that what we
realize with safeties, and this is
something that has really shifted over
the past couple of years, is that
there's a specific type of safety that a
Mike Vrabel and Zakur and Terrell
Williams defense is going to prioritize
and value. Right? There were guys who
just a couple of years ago looked like
they were going to be fixtures for the
Patriots and Kyle Duggar and also the
Bro Peppers and then both of them are
gone. Obviously, the Jaylen Hawkins for
Kevin Bard swap is one that brings tons
of familiarity, it's also a one-year
deal for a safety in his 30s is Kevin
By. So, if you could find a guy that
provides some of that ability to chop
off explosive plays down the field like
By does. He's got premier ball skills.
He led the NFL interceptions once again
last season. admired, but safety is
probably a bigger need than maybe is
currently being forecasted. And the
Patriots showed last year that you can
get some good players in the middle
rounds of the draft. Craig Woodson was
just excellent for them. And a guy that
was it 102nd overall, I think it was for
Craig. So, not quite in the middle of
the draft, but just prior to the
proverbial 50ard line of the 2025 NFL
draft.
>> Well, I know you got another mock draft
coming up. Do you want to tease that at
I don't want you to give anything away,
but you know, this is what we live and
breathe on here in the spring.
>> Yeah, pass catcher will be one of the
themes. Actually, a two round mock
draft. So, a pass catcher and but that
there will certainly be a note in there
that this could all change if AJ Brown
is eventually shipped to New England.
The delicate balance that, you know,
Elliot Wolf and Mike Vrabel are dealing
with is that, you know, there's no way
to agree to a deal that's contingent
upon getting done after June 1st. like
the NFL does not allow that. You could
have an agreement in principle, but it
can't be fully executed. So, for any
number of reasons, a deal that you think
is done on March 19th may not be done
once June 2nd rolls around. So, you
almost have to go into this draft uh
counting on receiver as a need. Address
it if you so desire. Keep in mind that
AJ Brown could become available, but I'm
sure the Patriots and Eagles have have
had plenty of conversations about how
realistic that could be and uh we still
have five weeks until the NFL draft. So,
even more time for them to kind of flesh
out the parameters of a potential deal.
A pass catcher will be a need there for
the Patriots. I would note that uh
they're in that sweet spot at the back
end of the first round as well that
teams will call, right? It's not just
teams that maybe want to get up into the
back end of the first round for a
quarterback. And this does feel like one
of those years where we could see a team
move up for Ty Simpson out of Alabama. I
think he will make it into the 20s. But
the other thing that I would note is
teams do want that fifth year of
contract control. Uh the Carolina
Panthers moved up just a couple of years
ago from 33 to 32 to get Xavier Legette,
the wide receiver out of South Carolina.
and and and it could be that they wanted
the fifth year of contract control.
That's the only motivation. It also
could be that if you know a team is
convinced that Seattle or whoever might
be picking at 32 is going to take who
they really want to at the top of the
second round, then they could be
motivated to jump ahead uh and get to
number 31. So tradeback is something
that I think almost every team likes to
do, especially in a draft class like
this. So wouldn't surprise me if the
Patriots are proactive and finding
suitors that could come up to number 31
overall just given the fact that I think
the caliber of player between 31 and 37
40 is pretty similar even in a draft in
which the Patriots have at least right
now the third most picks of any team in
the NFL.
>> A lot of uncertainty when you're down
there at the bottom of the first round.
Makes it a little bit more exciting I
think. Of course they trade out. Could
be a long night, but we'll let that
happen. Field, thank you so much for
taking the time and uh we'll continue to
look out for your mock drafts and uh see
what comes about in April.
>> Thanks, D. Appreciate you having me on.
>> All right, we're breaking down the
defensive backs today. That includes, of
course, the quarterbacks and the safety
group. Maybe not positions of
overwhelming need. Certainly not the
quarterback spot where the top three
guys are going to return Te, but why
don't you set the table a little bit for
us here uh at the quarterback spot? Of
course, Christian Gonzalez maybe up for
an extension. That's a big part.
>> Christian Gonzalez certified as one of
the best corners in the league.
Obviously, you don't know what the
extension situation is going to be. You
got Marcus Jones who got the extension
last season 2025. Carlton Davis coming
in for year two. Then you got some of
the younger guys, Kobe Miner, Charles
Woods. We had uh Marcel Dial off the
injury. So,
>> it's Listen, nothing wrong with taking a
quarterback, but we got some depth
there.
>> Yeah. Ev, what are we looking for at the
quarterback position right now? all
things considered what they have, but
just generally
>> I think that you know if you're looking
for somebody that's going to step in at
2026, it's probably another player on
the outside as insurance for either
Carlton Davis or Christian Gonzalez. If
you're looking for long-term maybe the
nickel spot gets in there a little bit
more and we can talk about as we blur
the lines here at defensive back between
safety and corner some of the bigger
nickel players that you know can come in
and add some size to that position. But
I think that's really what you're
looking for in terms of the immediate
future is a third outside corner that
can rotate in and maybe take some of the
load off those guys or if there's an
injury and then is there a bigger body
type that maybe you'd want to put inside
to help Marcus Jones out with you know
some of those big boys at tight end and
things like that.
>> Let's just rifle it off the top. This is
kind of four guys to me probably not
going to be there based on you know mock
drafts and of course Mansor Delane Avon
Terrell Colton Hood Gerard McCoy um Hood
McCoy I really like both those guys. Um
I don't know if there's a world where
that would ever happen. Um all those
guys are talented though but when I see
you know physical players that can play
a little bit of zone a little bit of man
that to me kind of speaks to what
they're looking for. Any of those top
four guys Chris for you that uh that you
enjoyed?
>> I mean you mentioned McCoy I think that
was one that really stuck out to me but
>> coming off of a knee injury right?
>> Yeah. So, I mean, you want to see where
he can come or sort of develop following
the injury, but you know, a guy that
stuck out to me personally, I'm gonna
kind of step another direction here, is
Brendan Cece. Um, you know, potential to
be a late first round pick. Uh, I know
there's a lot of speculation. Obviously,
the Chiefs just trade away Trent
McDuffy. So, they're going to be looking
for a corner in some sort of area there.
Um, but you know, quality guy, uh, sort
of sideline to sideline quarterback,
covers your outside, great against tight
ends, very strong, fast, ran a 43, 540,
like, you know, he's a guy that he's
he's a special DB.
>> Yeah. What about the top four, Ev? You
got anything on those guys?
>> I would just say with Colton Hood, like
he's probably the one guy that's
projected the most sort of at that back
end of the first round. I highly doubt
the Patriots are going to use the 31st
pick on a corner. Uh, but I was looking
at him a little bit the other day in the
the NFL.com Lance Zerline comparison,
it's Carlton Davis. So, if you're
looking for a player that kind of fits
the suit and fits that mold, if we're
going to have that conversation, uh,
but, you know, I would say the guys that
I wrote down to specifically highlight
today are more in that mid round, maybe
starting at the end of the third or
fourth round range because I think
that's kind of we're we're talking about
them drafting for depth, not necessarily
drafting for starters. with with Colton
Hood, who I really liked. It's kind of
one of those situations a lot of the
mocks have the Seahawks taken him. It
kind of makes sense since Reek left. So,
I mean, big physical corner. I like when
the corners can jam the receiver and
match up against the big guys. So, would
be a good fit. This just might not be
the year for it.
>> Yeah. I mean, staying kind of in these
top level guys, Chris Johnson from San
Diego State, another guy, sorry, uh
really athletic, great feet, you know,
not great size or long speed, but a
versatile guy.
>> Let's move on though to some of these,
you know, later round guys. And I'm just
going to bring up two that that I enjoy
watching. I I again looking guys with
some feistiness to their game. Keith
Abney from Arizona State and Dalon Ever
from Georgia. And Dalon Ever from
Georgia. I just I mean he's 611 196. He
ran a 4-38. He's played 41 games in the
SEC. Um to me, he just looks the part.
He's experienced. Uh I really just
responded to him. I don't know if you
did a ding-ding. What do you guys think?
>> Yeah, nailed it. Yeah. I mean, he's the
number one guy on my list right now cuz
I think, you know, probably starting at
the end of the third round is where his
name is going to be called. He had a
really great combine, and I wonder if
that pushes him up into securely into
that top 100 range. Well, you start to
talk about guys in their system that
they are playing a little bit more zone
coverage. So, you still want to have
that ability to play man-to-man, which I
think Everett has, but then you also
really are going to be foundationally a
zone coverage team. Uh that's ex you
just described the Georgia Bulldogs,
right? And I think a lot of the things
that Georgia does uh with their palms or
quarters coverages and things like that
are similar to the way the Patriots want
to play coverage on the outside. Great
athlete as I mentioned, you know, one of
the best testers at the combine. Ran in
the I want to say high 43s. I think 438.
>> Yeah. 61 196.
>> Yeah. He's got some size to him as well
with that kind of speed. So, we're
describing a guy that, you know, most
people are listening to this probably
like, "Well, why is this guy going in
the third or fourth round?" He might
not. You know, like that's the reality
of it. Now that we're getting into this
later stages, a lot of these consensus
boards, you see his name starting to
creep up into the third round and even
beyond.
>> Let's stop talking about him then. Maybe
maybe we can push him down.
>> Too much hype.
>> Did you guys have any thoughts on him? I
know I shared him as one of the names
that
>> No, no, not nothing directly on him
necessarily from me.
>> Yeah, I got some later guys. Um, I had
Willy Willie Lee. Just a good uh from
Texas A&M.
>> Willie three.
>> Yeah, Willy.
>> I think that's a great that's a great
name.
>> Willy three. Um, no, just a good mix
between man and zone. Um, you know,
could put multiple places. Good
developmental prospect. We're talking
about a depth guy. I also had Torion
Pride who ran a 432, which keep his
name. We'll talk about him and the
safeties, but you can't teach speed. So,
I think there's nothing wrong with
taking a quarterback who can run fast at
the later rounds.
>> Yeah, for me, for me, just to jump in,
take another later round guy. Uh, I
think Devin Moore from Florida. uh very
lengthy uh you know great in coverage,
good downfield, can stand upright when
he's backpedaling sometimes, but you
know, things these things can be
adjusted. I think these are important
things to focus on cuz like we talked
about at the top of this, you're getting
a developmental guy. You're getting a
guy that you can help grow and and sort
of adjust his gameplay and I mean Moore
has dealt with some injuries, but again
still has to develop, still has to grow,
but you get into an NFL system,
especially here in New England
potentially, you know, who knows what
could happen. So, uh, we mentioned Dylan
Everett, who I think is probably gonna
go high, uh, probably top 100 or at
least third round. Charles Demings from
Stephen F. Austin is kind of like the
other Dylan Everett, who's similar kind
of player, but smaller school and might
go in that fourth round. So, you look at
those picks at 125 and 131. you know, he
makes a lot of sense in that kind of
range, but still another 61, 190 pounds,
44 corner, you know, so has the size of
speed uh to play man-to-man. Uh probably
needs a little bit more seasoning and
zone coverage. Uh it would probably be
the next step for him. I also just be
got to mention Lorenzo Styles from Ohio
State just cuz he's a Buckeye and we
know who the head coach is. So, you
know, his brother Sunny is going to be
probably a top 10, top 15 pick in the
draft, but Lorenzo Styles, as we sort of
segue, I brought him up here because
we're just going to start talking about
the safeties. He's kind of like a nickel
safety hybrid type of player that played
a lot over the slot at Ohio State and
projects as a guy that can play
man-to-man out of the slot, but has some
size that maybe he can do some safety
things, too. So like him, Jaylen Kilgore
from South Carolina, uh that Genesis
Smith from Arizona, those are the types
of guys that have a little history of
playing pure slot uh corner uh that
maybe the Patriots could be interested
in. I I'm interested to see when uh
Lorenzo Styles goes cuz all the
attention at the combine was on his
brother and then he went out there and
had a ridiculous workout himself and
it's like what is this family and like
like what is going on?
>> Sunny and Lorenzo Styles, elite
athletes, great names.
>> Yeah. and his mom's like in the stands
and she's like rooting for both of them.
And I'm like, "Mom, like what did you
do?" And so I think Lorenzo Styles is
probably an early day three pick, you
know, maybe in the top 150. Yeah.
>> And I I you know, all the trades that
you look for.
>> Well, you you start to turn the page.
Why don't you set the table though for
us at the at the safety position because
there was a huge transition this year.
And I mean, I don't know how many people
would have expected that the 2025
Patriots were going to get rid of Kyle
Duggar and Jaba Bril Peppers, turn it
right over to rookie Craig Woodson. Uh
Jaylen Hawkins, primarily a special
teams player, comes in and starts. Now
you bring in Kevin Bard. I think we can
all agree, you know, there's some depth
questions here and and especially
long-term with the one-year deal. But
Ev, what do you see out of that position
right now when you look at these
prospects? What checks your box for this
is the Patriots kind of guy?
>> Coverage, coverage, coverage. Like I
feel like we're out of the days now with
the Patriots where playing in the box,
playing starting closer to the line of
scrimmage, uh, being able to, you know,
do basically like that hybrid linebacker
safety thing. I I don't know if we're in
that world anymore. I feel like now with
the Patriots defense, they want guys
that can cover a lot of grass on the
back end, that can play over the top of
the defense, that can play quarters,
that can match the slot. I think that's
probably one of the most important
things as uh in terms of the level of
difficulty of the assignment. You know,
when they go to uh 3x one and they go to
quarters and two by two, if they go to a
bunch formation offensively, those types
of things, usually the safety ends up in
man coverage on somebody. So, you need
someone in that mold that has a little
bit of coverage skills in man-to-man and
can run with people and can carry
verticals, can uh catch verticals down
the field, you know, 10, 12 yards off
the ball. So, it's not so much the Kyle
Duggars, the Jabriel Pepperses of the
world anymore. Now, it's the Craig
Woodsons, like the guys that can really
cover in the back end. That box needs to
be checked first and then we can start
worrying about physicality and run
defense.
>> I remember asking you something similar
during the season. and you're like,
well, you know, like Kevin Bard and now
here's Kevin Bernard. Of course, there's
a consensus top guy here, Caleb DS. Um,
I'm going to let you guys jump in on him
and and thean because I'm going to let
Evan uh go on Emanuel McNeel Warren
because I know he's got a little bit of
a
>> I got a crush on both him and Dylan
Dynamite
is awesome.
>> I mean, that that combine workout was
like
>> he's a beast. He's a beast. Threeear
starter ran like a 437 or something.
He's you watch his tape, he's
everywhere. Like that that's that's the
dream. I mean, Evan, would you say first
round or probably top 20? So, like
that's one of those things if if he's
there, like do you make the move? Like,
>> I think it's a worthy conversation right
now.
>> If he somehow slides like which I don't
think he will, but like you just got to
think Evan's talking about Yeah, he
might not start this year, but like
there's he's a beast. There's something
you can't pass up on.
>> Yeah. Yeah. What about down? We got to
talk about down Matt. I mean, look,
there's no hope of that, but him at the
combine talking about Matt Patricia, the
impact that he had. I mean, talk about a
guy that can do everything. Some team's
going to get a really good player.
>> There's sometimes when you like hear
about prospects and you hear the
hyperbole of like, "This is the best
safety prospect since Ed Reid." And I'm
like, "No, this might be the best safety
prospect since Ed Reid." Like, that
might actually be true. Uh, in this
case, I I I don't a guy that wears as
many hats as he does and has the ability
to play in all three levels of the
defense. and Matt Patricia used him as a
pro safety last year, moving him around
and hunting matchups and putting out
fires and all that kind of stuff that
you saw uh for years here in New England
with their safety. So, uh he the hype is
100% real with him. You know, I I did
honestly haven't watched him a ton
closely cuz why get into it? You know,
reason to. Uh but I think that the one
thing that you did hear a little bit
with him coming out of the combine is
maybe some concerns about his knee and
uh his injury. not history in terms of
what he happened at Ohio State because
nothing really happened, but his
longevity of his career because of maybe
some uh of those types of medical
things, but that's like maybe a team
that's picking 11th that like and I'm
making that up, but like maybe that is
trying to get him to fall or something
like that because there's there's really
not a lot of holes in his game.
>> No, he he's an absolute stud. I mean,
Caleb D is one of my personal favorite
safeties in this drive. He's I know he's
everybody's favorite safety in this
draft, but he's just so dynamic and fun
to watch. And I mean, we talked about
these multi-layer guys like Craig
Woodson, great find for the Patriots,
especially last year.
>> Uh he's a guy, you know, you talk about
playing like deep third of the field,
kind of ball hog safety style, what you
need now. And and Craig Woodson has
added that piece to the run, like solid,
one of the better tacklers from the
secondary. And Caleb DS, I mean, he can
do it both ways, too. No,
>> I was really impressed with Woodson
though this year, just the quick aside,
like just he looks like a free safety.
He understands how to navigate traffic
and how to get the ball and takes good
angles. Uh it's a great building piece
and especially his playoff was
outstanding. Um but just moving on to,
you know, some favorites. Um I I'm not
going to talk about him. Bug Clark, you
know, one favorite of mine. The two guys
I want to mention though that I just is
AJ Holly from LSU and Traden Stuks from
Arizona. Um two guys that I kept coming
back to, uh Holly ran a 452. not great,
but he just he's got the build and and I
mean maybe to Evan's point, he's not
quite the run all over the place kind of
a guy. Um, but he's just one where I I
you're drawn to certain kind of players
and I don't know, he looks the part to
me. Maybe he would play a third safety
kind of role. Uh, and then with Stokes,
there's there's no speed concern uh with
him 4-33, but just with him watching
him, he did everything that Evan talked
about. He can play off the overhang, he
can blitz, he can play in the back half.
Um, those were just two guys probably,
you know, second, third round in there,
maybe not quite the matchup, but those
were just two guys to me that that stood
out.
>> Yeah, Hollyy's an interesting player.
Uh, he's one of the more fun safeties to
me in this class because of how he hits.
He's like one of the only he's one of
the only guys other than McNeel Warren
who's like really physical. Uh, these
other guys that we're going to talk
about are cover players and rangy
players and, you know, 195, 200 lb, run
well. Uh Holly is the one guy that uh
really uh is an enforcer over the middle
of the field. Now I think the issue with
him though is that he's a little bit
rigid, a little bit stiff. Uh he doesn't
quite have the sideline to sideline
range over the top of the defense. So
he's going to be a scheme specific
player and he's not going to be for
everybody and his role in the NFL is
going to be really really important.
like some team is going to have to
figure out how to keep him out of those
like dynamic foot races down the road.
>> Brian Branch is
>> maybe a little, you know what I mean?
>> Yeah. I mean, I know it's a little
different, but it's similar kind of
you're going to have to do something
special with
>> he's one of the biggest safeties in the
class, too. You know, uh 215 lbs is big
for a safety these days. So, uh he's one
of those we we glossed over McNeel
Warren. So, please go back to my I'll
just I'll just gush for a second. Uh,
you know, I think that with him, you
know, I I see a lot of highlights about
him playing in the deep part of the
field at Toledo and and making plays on
the football and I I think that's in
there, but I think really his destiny is
that Kyle Hamilton Nick and Manwari role
where he's playing more in the box or
over the slot specifically uh in a lot
of the you know nickel and dime packages
where they use big safeties these days
in those roles. uh his ability to uh you
know make plays on the football uh his
length, his tackling ability, uh his
ability to take on blocks and hold up
run plays uh in that sense are all just
plus plus plus traits across the board.
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> No, I don't I don't want to cut I just
Is there any chance one of those I mean
obviously not downs, but is there any
chance that one of those top three
safeties is is there at 31?
>> I I don't think so. I mean, McNeel
Warren's probably the best case like in
terms of somebody falling there and I do
think the Patriots reportedly had him in
for a 30 30 visit. So, they obviously
feel like he might be uh somebody that
could slip through the cracks to 31. I
think the two things that maybe make him
fall that way. Now, Quinan Mitchell went
to Toledo, so it's not like Toledo has
never had a guy that they produced in
the NFL, but it's not a big-time
program. So, you are seeing a level of,
you know, jump in level of competition
from Toledo to the NFL. Uh, I would also
say like I I was kind of getting at,
he's a taller, leggier corner uh safety.
So like when he's back there, I don't
know if he's going to be a true free
safety at the NFL level because of that.
>> The thing though, despite his height, I
feel like a big thing for him is like
you mentioned is his physicality.
>> Like being a safety and being that
physical is is exactly what a team wants
to see. And I feel like that's such a
big big role to fill uh especially here
in New England. So I mean I really like
his physicality. I mean, he had nine
forced fumbles.
>> He's a tackling machine.
>> Force fumbles, peanut Evan's
talking about ball hawks and stuff,
which I like, but I like my safety still
to hit. Like, I grew up with Cam
Chancellor. So, like I mentioned with
the corners, there was um Pride from
Missouri who ran a four 4-3. So,
>> this guy stands out. Robert Spears
Jennings from Oklahoma. So, uh Pride
Pride ran a 43 uh 432 at like 185. This
guy is 6'2 205 and ran the same speed
like he's a train like like he's gonna
be a later round guy but like just
physical on the ball there. And then for
the more realistic day two thing I like
um Zachie Wheatley from Penn State
another 30 visit guy.
>> Yeah, he he definitely has the cover
skills that they're going to look for. I
wrote down in my notes with him pure
free safety. Like I think that he's a
pure over-the-top player. He's got
length, but he's a little bit lean in
his frame right now. I but I think his
movement skills and coverage and his
ability to play over the top of the
defense are are really really good. So,
I think there's a group of those types
of players. You know, him Ramsay from
USC kind of fits that mole. Uh you know,
those guys on day two. You can you can
talk about
>> HE'S TEEING YOU UP, CHRIS. He's setting
you up.
>> You know, those are the types of
players. Uh you know, Deuce mentioned
Bud Clark who's a crush of mine in like
the third or fourth round. Uh those guys
are if you're looking for people that
can cover, you know, that's what you're
talking about. And I also want to talk
about Genesis Smith a little bit too,
but you go ahead with
>> No, it's all good. No, you you touched
on it's the coverage thing for Ramsey.
Very very Yes,
>> very appealing uh from Ramsay. Uh you
know, you can put him deep, you can put
him in the slot. Um you know, really
trusted in coverage. He sees the ball
well and I think his ability to crash on
receivers and really force that impact
and force the ball out of the hands. I
think that's a that's a major a major
positive for him and I mean he had the
knee injury that that kind of sidelined
him the rest of 2025 but again like just
another guy kind of coming in can still
develop and you know possible day two
day three guy. So
>> I like what you're getting out with ball
disruption because I think that's you
know not enough turnovers last year. I
think that's something that really kind
of it gives the defense its personality
when they when they turn the ball over.
Uh open the floor. Anybody got another
Evan? I'm sure you
>> I'll just rattle off a couple more. So,
Genesis Smith from Arizona interests me
because in 24 he played the nickel spot
there at slot corner and then in 25 he
went back and played a little bit more
free and uh had a lot of more uh you
know interceptions and ball production
there. But I actually watched some of
his 24 tape at slot corner and I thought
it was pretty solid too. So he's a guy
that can do a little bit of both of
those things like kind of like a free
nickel hybrid which is sort of what I
think they want their safeties to do and
maybe what they could be looking for
long term. Uh Jaylen Kilgore is a
favorite of mine. He's a pure nickel
like big nickel uh that could come in
and you know maybe play when you play a
team that's going to play multiple tight
ends or play a fullback or something
like that and you want to be bigger in
your nickel package. Uh I think Jaylen
Kilgore is one of those types of guys.
You mentioned Bud Clark like that that
to me looks like Craig Woodson 2.0. You
know he can play, you know, quarters
coverage, he can play manto man. He can
fill the alleys in the run game.
>> 15 picks. Yeah,
he's he's a ball hawk. He gets his hands
on football sometimes at the detriment.
Sometimes he takes too many risks trying
to get hands on footballs, but uh I
think that he's the type of guy that
kind of when I watched him, I was like,
well, the Patriots ask their safeties to
do this, they ask him to do that, they
ask him to do that, and he was kind of
checking all the boxes. Uh then you sort
of get into like the VJ Pays and he was
VJ P, you know, like kind of get a
little bit lower in the draft. Um, you
know, uh, Jacob Thomas from Miami. Like,
now we're talking, you know, maybe fifth
round, sixth round safety prospects that
all do a little bit, but VJ Payne's an
interesting one. He's he's a fun player.
>> Yeah, I liked him, too. I mean, that
same thing you said. I saw him at free
safety. Saw him in the box. He's 6'3,
206 with a 4-4, 42 game starter,
captain. Um, yeah, I like that. I think
like that to me makes sense. Like day
three, early day three, you get your guy
to learn behind Bard and Woodson and
then maybe next year he's able to take
over. Yeah, that's the question is are
they are they looking for the future
starting safety of the New England
Patriots or are they looking for a
complimentary player to the 2026 New
England Patriots? Because if it's the
complimentary player then we're looking
at the box nickel types that can play
against bigger personnel because they're
going to have Bard, they're going to
have Craig Woodson. Those guys are going
to play in the deep part of the field.
If they're looking for Kevin Byron's on
a one-year contract, he's 33 years old,
yada yada yada. Then we're talking about
drafting one of these like Bud Clarks or
something like that that can cover
people.
>> This is some crossover. And I mean, I
think we'll probably talk a lot about
this on Draft Countdown as we get closer
to the draft is just, you know, how do
they get more in the tank to cover tight
ends? Do they, you know, try to help at
the linebacker position? Is that a co a
coverage position? Or are they looking
at, you know, one of these guys like
Holly who could maybe play in the box
and kind of play some of that role?
Interesting how they're going to
approach I don't think any of us know,
but that's why we're here on Patriots
Draft Countdown. So, want to thank you
guys for tuning in this week. We're
going to be back next week with more
Patriots draft content.